SIMONA DASSI

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Via F. Baracca, 37, 20851 Lissone (Italy) +39 346 81 11 689

omismail@libero.it

http://www.linkedin.com/in/simona-dassi

Sex Female | Date of birth 27/07/1976 | Nationality Italian



EDUCATION

2002 Degree in Economics 110/110 with honors

WORK EXPERIENCE

Summary

I am a Professional with a solid experience in Sales & Marketing, in multinational companies of the IT sector. In these years I have developed skills in Marketing, Business Development, Sales and Management of complex negotiations both at local and international level. I have the capabilities to create efficient and productive collaboration environments that have allowed me to bring important advantages to customer organizations such as optimizing business processes with consistent saving, introduction of innovative technology with a significant impact on economic results and company turnover. What distinguishes me is the "care" for the customer, understanding his needs in detail, analyzing them to find the best solution and guarantee his satisfaction. I am a very collaborative person who loves working in team, I am a person very determined who puts passion in any activities she does!

Experiences

Key Account Manager - Selecta Group

June 2019 - Present

As Key Account Manager my main responsibility is develop new business both acquiring new customer and increase our presence in the customer with high potential.

Key Responsibilities:

- Definition of the commercial plan
- Acquisition and development of medium-sized and large corporate clients
- Market analysis and client segmentation
- Competition analysis for traditional services and positioning new value proposition

Account Manager – BU Large Customer at Ricoh

July 2018 - June 2019

As Account Manager my task is position Ricoh Offering and address the needs of the Enterprise Customer cross segment supporting them to the Digital Transformation.

Key Responsibilities:

- Gain share of wallet in the hunting customer and increase the overall positioning in the farming ones
- Increase and maintain strategic relationship with the C-Level in the top customers
- Solutions Proposed: Managed Print Services, Communication Services, IT services (Personal

Sales Account Manager, Printing and Solutions at HP

January 2017 – July 2018

As Printing Account Manager I work on selected Enterprise Customer in different segments (FSI, Retail, Manufacturing and Pharma) where I have the task to develop the printing business and managed print solution.

Key Responsibilities:

- Create HP share of wallet in the "new logo customers" on printing business
- Establish and maintain a professional and consultative relationship with the customer at C-level in the top large accounts
- Create dedicated business plan for the strategic accounts to build a strong pipeline and long term collaboration
- Maintain partnership with key reseller and distributors (SI, VAR, IT Reseller, Software House) and develop collaboration with new partners
- Propose new solutions and create new business opportunities in terms of revenue and margin
- Manage an accurate forecast on month base and a solid pipeline on half base

Partner Supplies Business Developer Manager at HP

February 2014 – December 2016

As Supplies Business Developer I manage a list of the top account customers in Enterprise and High end Mid Market segment with the goal to find the best solution for the customer to manage the 'supplies business".

Key Responsibilities:

- -"Protect" the supplies business in the large account with a big Installed Base
- Recruit new customers to develop new business
- Work with the top partner in order to develop a common strategy on strategic customers
- Create a strong pipeline with consistent opportunities

Channel Marketing Manager and Partner Business Developer - Printing and Personal Systems (PPS) at Hewlett-Packard

January 2007 – January 2014

As Channel Marketing and Business Developer Manager in PPS division I am responsible for all comarketing programs and activities that involving channel partners: Reseller (traditional reseller, VAR and ISV) and Distributors. I worked closed with sales (indirect sales MidMarket and SMB) and category manager for Printing and Personal System products.

Kev Responsibilities:

- Develop an overall business plan for all the partners selected with responsibility of the budget management and KPI (ROI, sell-out, pipeline and funnel)
- Develop, implement and execute programs and campaigns in alignment with central marketing, product manager, Small/Midmarket Sales Strategy
- Develop a joint marketing plan with Partners (VAR, SI, Distributors) with multi touch point for new customers and retention customers: events, promotions, media and communication plan, lead generation activities, digital marketing campaigns SEM/SEO, Social, Google

Software Marketing Manager

January 2005 – December 2006

As Marketing Manager I am the focal point of contact for sales and customer for all the marketing activities.

Key Responsibilities:

- Develop the business plan for software business focusing on top solution and strategic customer
- Implement lead generation and awareness plan
- Develop and integrated communication plan: offline and online adv and PR, external and internal communications (online, social, newsletter, intranet, etc.)
- Manage events both at local and international level (conference, seminars, workshop, training,

roadshow, trades, etc.)

- Sales support for customer presentation and reporting

Services Marketing at Hewlett-Packard

June 2002 - December 2004

Support the program manager to develop and implement marketing programs and activities on HP services.

Key Responsibilities:

- Creation and implementation of the marketing plan, monitoring of the activities and results
- Funds management in line with EMEA guidelines
- Support for events and lead generation activities
- Support the sales for reporting and presentations

Accomplished results:

CASE 1

- Contact with a large banking group with transactional installed base distributed throughout the national territory;
- Analysis of procurement processes and distribution process for services and consumable within the bank (HQ and branches);
- Optimization of the model in collaboration with the different players with consequent improvement of the efficiency of the model of procurement and governance of the entire printing environment;
- Saving for the customer with consequent release of resources and technology optimization.

CASE 2

Renewal with a Key Client of the contract only for Italy contrary to the choices of the Group (who had chosen another brand in Europe. 250 machines about 1.2MT of contract) thanks to:

- Excellent relationship with the Italian customer (the result of a close collaboration with all CIO, CPO, CTO levels);
- Analysis of the current scenario with evidence of strengths, investments already depreciated, processes to be optimized thanks to our solutions already in place;
- Saving of about 15/20% current solution vs new competition solution;
- flexible SLAs definition on the basis of their specific needs;
- Technological upsell.

SKILLS AND TRAINING

- Customer focus approach
- Strong problem solving approach
- Good attitude to work in team not only "direct team" but also "virtual and extended"
- Selling solution approach (complex selling)
- Selling to different C-Level (CIO, CFO and CPO)
- Public Speaking
- Financial knowledge
- Good level of English

In compliance with the Italian legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize you to use and process my personal details contained in this document.